# KAUSHIK KOILADA

Senior Data Engineer 

Hyderabad, India

koiladakaushik.98@gmail.com♦ in Koilada Kaushik ♦ 🗘 k-root

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Senior Data Engineer with 3 years experience in various fields including Front-end and Back-end Application Development, data ETL pipelines with proficient experience of Google Cloud Platform looking forward to put my best of skill sets to engineer solutions and learn through upcoming challenges.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Indian Institute of Information Technology SriCity, Bachelor of Technology

2015-2019

CGPA - 8.23

Knowledge through curriculum designed to be industry-ready with multiple TA-ship experiences. Graduate level accomplishments can be found here

#### **SKILLS**

Languages Python, SQL, R, Golang, JavaScript, HTML Frameworks & Systems Flask, Angular, Git, Docker, Terraform

Google Cloud Platform Compute Engine, App Engine, Cloud Run, Cloud Functions Kubernetes,

Cloud Dataflow, Cloud Composer, Cloud PubSub, BigQuery, Cloud SQL, Firebase,

Cloud AutoML, Cloud Vision, Document AI, IAM, Networking services

Soft Skills Effective Communication, Flexibility, Ownership, Quick Learner, Open to Challenges

Fields of Experience Web Development, Google Cloud Platform, Data Migration and ML Pipelines

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Senior Data Engineer, SpringML

Dec 2021 - Present

- Leading and contributing towards multiple projects and teams with active client communications.
- Established and integrated Cloud Resources with custom-built data extraction pipeline.
- Active involvement in training colleagues for projects and Google Cloud Certifications.
- Research through latest releases and technologies.

### Data Engineer, SpringML

Nov 2020 - Dec 2021

- Engineered and owned multiple end to end data extraction pipelines using GCP for various use-cases.
- Developed and actively enhanced back-end and front-end web applications.
- Researched and gained proficient experience with Google Cloud Platform(GCP).
- Implemented Python based modular functionalities to achieve use-cases.
- Trained and provided resources to colleagues for certifications.
- Recognized for work and impact through employee highlight.

### Associate Data Scientist, SpringML

June 2019 - Oct 2020

- Gained hands-on experience certified with Google Cloud Platform(GCP).
- Shadowed project involving on-premise to cloud migration.
- Developed generic data extraction framework leveraging it for multiple independent use-cases.
- Active participation in team building activities and knowledge transfers.

#### Safe Travels - State of Hawaii

- Description: Application serving mandatory travel and health form for tourists and residents travelling to Hawaii to reopen the tourism of Hawaii in the pandemic, further evolved into much advanced application handling overall management of travel to Hawaii including automation and integration of several means of providing travellers exception from quarantine ensuring smooth travel.
- Orchestrated the automation pipeline responsible for granting quarantine exceptions to the users with valid RT-PCR reports leveraging Google Cloud Document AI.
- Programmed REST based API endpoints in flask for the application back-end.
- Built the Angular based front-end serving the application and integrated with the Flask back-end.
- Leveraged services of Google Cloud Platform(GCP) to deploy and serve the application for compute, storage and data warehousing.
- Implemented CI/CD pipeline with Google Cloud Build and Git.
- Leading the team with developments, enhancements, security review, code reviews and deployments.
- Maintained technical and user documentations of the implementations as necessary.

### DocBot - Document Extraction Framework

- Description: Framework, supported with user interface, built to extract data from given document which can be customised and scaled to fit any document extraction use-case.
- Developed and enhanced multiple UI components serving the framework.
- Developed several REST based API endpoints in flask for the application back-end.
- Engineered asynchronous processing of documents to scale for solutions demanding heavy load.
- Leveraged and integrated services of Google Cloud Platform(GCP).
- Implemented CI/CD pipeline with Google Cloud Build and Git.
- Took ownership of the application and spawned various services leveraging this framework to solve many large scale document extraction projects.
- Automated deployments using terraform.
- Maintained technical and user documentations of the implementations as necessary.
- Showcased the application for various potential clients as part of pre-sales activities.

## **Data Migration - Digital River**

- Description: Data migration from on-premise Oracle database to Google Cloud.
- Shadowed initially to understand the production grade implementation of the solution.
- Refactored legacy application to enhanced python based implementation.
- Contributed to micro-services setup responsible for data migration and transformation.
- Leveraged and integrated services of Google Cloud Platform(GCP).

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Google Cloud - Associate Cloud Engineer

### COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT

- Trained various batches of incoming employees to get certifications.
- Instrumentalist self taught instrumentalist with active participation in institute, company and various other gatherings and events.
- Public Speaking addressed and organized several sessions addressing audience and clients.